let's look at the solution to our block
number quiz if we have a 32 byte block
size and a 16-bit address like this the
question is what is the block offset and
the block number for a 32 byte block the
block offset will determine where within
the 32 bytes are we we need 5 bits to
tell us that because 2 to the 5 is 32 so
we need 5 bits to tell us which of the
32 bytes are we interested in accessing
that means that the least significant 5
bits of this address are the block
offset so the block offset is this the
remaining bits of the address are the
block number they are telling us which
of the 32 byte blocks contains this
address so this is our block number